<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:space="preserve" n="50">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Privacy and Cookie Policy</title>
                <editor xml:id="cmr">Charlotte Roueché</editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Centre for Computing in the Humanities, King's College London</authority>
                <idno type="filename">About</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p>Creative Commons licence Attribution UK 2.0
                        (<ref>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/</ref>)</p>
                    <p>All reuse or distribution of this work must contain somewhere a link back to the
                        URL <ref>http://inslib.kcl.ac.uk/</ref></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p/>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="text">
                <div type="section">
                    <p> This privacy and cookie policy applies to completed project sites that are currently maintained by King’s Digital Lab under a Service Level Agreement. </p></div>
                
                <div type="section"><head>How do we collect information?</head>
                    <p>We will obtain personal information from you when you contact us via an online form, if present on this site, or through direct contact via e-mail. Projects Principal Investigators may also receive the same information about you.</p></div>
                
                <div type="section"><head>How do we use this information?</head>
                    <p>This information is used to gather feedback about access to this site and how it is used. In addition, KDL may use the submitted data to resolve technical issues you encounter, to respond to requests for assistance, and to repair and improve our service.</p>
                <p>For more general information on cookies see the Wikipedia article on <ref target="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie">HTTP Cookies</ref>.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="section"><head>How do we use Cookies?</head>
                    <p>We use cookies for a variety of reasons detailed below. Unfortunately in most cases there are no industry standard options for disabling cookies without completely disabling the functionality and features they add to this site. It is recommended that you leave on all cookies if you are not sure whether you need them or not in case they are used to provide a service that you use.</p></div>
                
                <div type="section"><head>Disabling Cookies</head>
                    <p>You can prevent the setting of cookies by adjusting the settings on your browser (see your browser Help for how to do this). Be aware that disabling cookies will affect the functionality of this and many other websites that you visit. Disabling cookies will usually result in also disabling certain functionality and features of the this site. Therefore it is recommended that you do not disable cookies.</p></div>
                <div type="section"><head>The Cookies we set</head>
                    <p><emph>Forms related cookies</emph>. When you submit data to through a form such as those found on contact pages or comment forms, cookies may be set to remember your user details for future correspondence.</p>
                    
                    <p><emph>Third party Cookies</emph>. In some special cases we also use cookies provided by trusted third parties. The following section details which third party cookies you might encounter through this site.
                        This site uses Google Analytics which is one of the most widespread and trusted analytics solution on the web for helping us to understand how you use the site and ways that we can improve your experience. These cookies may track things such as how long you spend on the site and the pages that you visit so we can continue to produce engaging content.
                        For more information on Google Analytics cookies, see the official <ref target="https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245">Google Analytics page</ref>.</p></div>
                
                <div type="section"><head>More information</head>
                    <p>Hopefully that has clarified things for you and as was previously mentioned if there is something that you are not sure whether you need or not, it is usually safer to leave cookies enabled in case they do interact with one of the features you use on this site. However, if you would like to have more information please email us (kdl-info@kcl.ac.uk) or visit <ref target="https://kdl.kcl.ac.uk/">King’s Digital Lab</ref> and read our <ref target="https://www.kdl.kcl.ac.uk/privacy-policy/">Privacy and Cookie Policy</ref>.</p></div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>