<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:space="preserve" n="30">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Sponsors</title>
                <editor xml:id="cmr">Charlotte Roueché</editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Centre for Computing in the Humanities, King's College London</authority>
                <idno type="filename">Sponsors</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p>Creative Commons licence Attribution UK 2.0
                     (<ref>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/</ref>)</p>
                    <p>All reuse or distribution of this work must contain somewhere a link back to the
                        URL <ref>http://inslib.kcl.ac.uk/</ref></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p/>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
             <div type="text">
                 <p>The first sponsors of our work in <ref target="https://sourceforge.net/p/epidoc/wiki/Home/">EpiDoc</ref> were the <ref target="https://www.leverhulme.ac.uk/">Leverhulme Trust</ref>, who, in 2002, funded Charlotte Roueché and Tom Elliott to work on 
                     the development of EpiDoc for publishing the 
                     Inscriptions of Aphrodisisias in 2002 (see <ref target="http://www.epapp.kcl.ac.uk/">EPAPP</ref>). 
                     The resultant publications were funded by the Arts and Humanities Research Board (later the <ref target="https://ahrc.ukri.org/">Arts and Humanities Research Council</ref>) 
                     (see <ref target="http://insaph.kcl.ac.uk/index.html">InsAph</ref>)</p>
                 <p>In 2007 we received a new grant from the Leverhulme Trust to publish the corpus of the Inscriptions of Roman Cyrenaica, eastern Libya. 
                     The project has taken a long time, but there have been gains along the way.
                 </p>
                 <p>In 2008 Elliott and Roueché received a grant from <ref target="https://www.jisc.ac.uk/">JISC</ref> in the UK and the 
                     <ref target="https://www.neh.gov/">National Endowment for the Humanities</ref> in the USA for a collaborative project to explore the publication of inscriptions in 
                 association with geodata (see <ref target="https://concordia.atlantides.org/">Concordia</ref>); 
                     this enabled the publication of the <ref target="http://inslib.kcl.ac.uk/irt2009/index.html">Inscriptions of Roman Tripolitania</ref>, 
                     western Libya, in 2009, 
                 from which we gained important understandings of how to publish the material from Cyrenaica.
               </p>
                 <p>On the basis of the geographical data collected for the Concordia project Dr Hafed Walda went on to collect the relevant geodata for Cyrenaica; 
                     he was funded by a Libyan Heritage Management Fellowship provided by Global Business Services. These data were then deployed in the 
                   <ref target="http://www.slsgazetteer.org/">Heritage Gazetteer of Libya</ref>; some of the underlying structure was drawn from work funded by the <ref target="http://www.leventisfoundation.org/en/">A.G Leventis Foundation</ref>, 
                     for the <ref target="http://www.cyprusgazetteer.org/">Heritage Gazetteer of Cyprus</ref>, but the main grant came from 
                     the <ref target="https://www.societyforlibyanstudies.org/">Society for Libyan Studies</ref>.</p>
                 <p>In 2016 Dr Gabriel Bodard, a member of the team, received a grant from the <ref target="https://mellon.org/">Andrew W. Mellon Foundation</ref> to 
                     develop EFES, a new publication platform for texts prepared in EpiDoc. In 2018 Roueché received a grant from the Society for Libyan Studies to 
                 set up the Cyrenaican corpus in EFES. A further grant from the Society has enabled the current publication.</p>
             </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
