<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:space="preserve" n="20">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>The team</title>
                <editor xml:id="cmr">Charlotte Roueché</editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Centre for Computing in the Humanities, King's College London</authority>
                <idno type="filename">Tram</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p>Creative Commons licence Attribution UK 2.0
                        (<ref>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/uk/</ref>)</p>
                    <p>All reuse or distribution of this work must contain somewhere a link back to the
                        URL <ref>http://inslib.kcl.ac.uk/</ref></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p/>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="text">
                <head>Editorial team</head>
                <p>Joyce Reynolds (<ref target="http://viaf.org/viaf/25924">VIAF</ref>,  
                    <ref target="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joyce_Reynolds_(classicist)">Wikipedia</ref>, 
                    <ref target="https://www.thebritishacademy.ac.uk/fellows/joyce-reynolds-FBA/">British Academy</ref>) 
                    collected and prepared almost all the texts presented here, with the support of many colleagues in Libya and elsewhere.</p>
                <p>Charlotte Roueché (<ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0002-3606-2049">ORCID</ref>) continued and standardised the editing, 
                    adding further texts and refernces, bibliography and translations. 
                </p>
                <p>Gabriel Bodard (<ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0002-8566-6666">ORCID</ref>) worked with Reynolds and Roueché 
                    on the editing and standardisation of texts, and also oversaw the digitisation and the construction of the publication, 
                    and use of EpiDoc standards. He was responsible for training many research assistants, 
                    student volunteers and other collaborators who worked on the project.</p>
                
                <p>Catherine Dobias-Lalou (<ref target="http://viaf.org/viaf/29572722">VIAF</ref>) provided significant editorial assistance, 
                    and contributed texts and images; she also provided some translations, 
                    as did Alice Bencivenni (<ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0001-5778-8677">ORCID</ref>), Hugues Berthelot 
                    (<ref target="http://viaf.org/viaf/215147724764164590887">VIAF</ref>)  and Muna Abdelhamed (<ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0002-8413-0931">ORCID</ref>). We have received specific contributions 
                    from Denis Feissel (<ref target="http://viaf.org/viaf/36918084">VIAF</ref>) and Benet Salway (<ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0001-8070-4136">ORCID</ref>).</p>
                <p>Hafed Walda provided geodata, which formed the basis from 
                    which Neil Jakeman created the Heritage Gazetteer of Libya; 
                    Walda also contributed an important collection of photographs, as did Dorothy Thorn (<ref target="http://viaf.org/viaf/56142832">VIAF</ref>) 
                    and Donald White (<ref target="http://viaf.org/viaf/14991227">VIAF</ref>).</p>
                <p>Muna Haroun provided Arabic tranlsations.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="list">
                <head>Research assistants</head>
                <p>Valentina Asciutti (2008–10)</p>
                <p>Caroline Barron (2010–12), <ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0003-4878-5620">ORCID</ref></p>
                <p>Ljuba Bortolani (2011–13)</p>
                <p>Eleonora Litta (2007-14), <ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0002-0499-997X">ORCID</ref></p>
                <p>Pietro Liuzzo (2008–10), <ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0001-5714-4011">ORCID</ref></p>
                <p>Maggie Robb (2008–09), <ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0002-3355-1672">ORCID</ref></p>
                <p>Charlotte Tupman (2007–08), <ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0002-4008-024X">ORCID</ref></p>
                <p>Raffaele Viglianti (2012-16), <ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0003-3094-139X">ORCID</ref></p>
            </div>
            <div type="text">
                <head>Placement students and other volunteers:</head>
                
                <p>
                    Maria Lucia Amadio (2010–11), 
                    Davide Bellini (2014),
                    Gillian Bentley (2010),
                    Maria Giorgia Di Antonio (2010–11),
                    Lucy Felmingham (2009–10),
                    Lousie Flynn (2008–09),
                    Susan Fogarty (2010),
                    Claudia Greco (2011),
                    Lourdes Moya (2010),
                    Adam Steene (2007–08),
                    Duncan Taylor (2008–09),
                    Paola Tomasi (2011)
                </p>
            </div>
            <div type="text">
                <head>Further development and design of IRCyr EFES interface</head>
                <p>Simona Stoyanova, <ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0003-3914-9569">ORCID</ref> </p>
                <p>Irene Vagionakis, <ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0002-1918-7333">ORCID</ref>    </p>
            </div>
            <div type="text"><head>Technical development</head>
                <p>The project was based at the Centre for Computing in the Humanities/Department of Digital Humanities and subsequently at King's Digital Lab, King's College London.</p>
                <p>Zaneta Au (CCH) was involved in the early planning.</p>
                <p>Arianna Ciula, <ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0003-4247-1073">ORCID</ref>  (KDL), Deputy Director and Senior Research Software Analyst, 
                    supported requirements elicitation as part of KDL effort on archiving and sustainability of legacy projects.</p>
                <p>Ginestra Ferraro <ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0001-8573-1432">ORCID</ref> (KDL), Senior Research Software UI/UX Designer, contributed to the design of IRCyr and HGL.</p>
                <p>Neil Jakeman, <ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0003-4049-3789">ORCID</ref> (KDL), Senior Research Software Analyst, refined the development and front-end of HGL, 
                    still hosted at KDL.</p>
                
                <p>Brian Maher, <ref target="https://orcid.org/0000-0001-6602-6834">ORCID</ref>  (KDL), Senior Research Software Engineer and Systems Administrator, 
                    responsible for the physical infrastructure on which IRCyr is currently hosted.</p> 
                <p>Pam Mellen (KDL), Research Software Project Manager responsible for managing KDL archiving and sustainability effort.</p>
                <p>Jamie Norrish (CCH/DDH), independent Developer, worked on EFES.</p>
                <p>Miguel Vieira (KDL), Principal Research Software Engineer, worked on the architecture and development of Kiln on which EFES is based.</p>
                
                <p>Tim Watts (KDL), Senior Research Software Systems Manager, is responsible for the physical infrastructure on which IRCyr is currently hosted.</p> 
            </div>
            
            
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
